Guide to the Moosewood Collective records, 1973-2010.
Moosewood Collective records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Moosewood Collective records, 1973-2010.
6882
Moosewood Collective.
4.0 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of Moosewood, Inc., including menus from the restaurant and special events, work on cookbooks, files on publicity and public recognition, restaurant policies and management, photographs, and correspondence.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Moosewood Restaurant opened in Ithaca, NY in 1973. Moosewood, Inc. is a collectively owned business whose members share responsibilities and participate in the various jobs necessary to run what has grown from a very small natural foods restaurant to become a larger and more diversified company with a line of salad dressings, soups, and frozen main-dish entrees. With an emphasis on healthful natural foods cuisine, Moosewood has been acclaimed as a driving force in the world of creative vegetarian cooking.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of Moosewood, Inc., including menus from the restaurant and special events, work on cookbooks, files on publicity and public recognition, restaurant policies and management, photographs, and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Moosewood Collective.
Subjects:
Cookbooks--United States.; Cooperative societies--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Employee ownership.; Vegetarian cooking.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Simple Suppers: proposal and work files (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Simple Suppers: publicity and records (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cookbook design (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Cookbook publicity, James Beard nomination (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence re illustrations (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Graphics (Box 1, Folder 9-13)
- Photography slides for Moosewood Restaurant cooks for a crowd cookbook (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Daily special cover art (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cookbook design (Box 1, Folder 16)
- miami book fair international (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Original recipe drafts from Sundays at Moosewood (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cookbooks: copy and clippings (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Reviews, misc., new classics (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Moosewood Celebrates (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Tours - cookbooks (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Publicity, James Beard Award (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Reviews: Sundays at Moosewood Restaurant cookbook (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
- New cookbook ideas (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Jeralyn’s press kit (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Reviews/new recipes from Moosewood Cookbook (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Article possibility (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Reviews/Cooks for Crowd (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Reviews/Low-fat Cookbook (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Cookbook publicity/[press] releases (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Moosewood books in catalogs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Moosewood policy notebook, mid-1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Excerpts, Moosewood dream book (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Photos - mid-80s-early 90s: Moosewood Collective Restaurant & friends, 1980-1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Ads + sponsorships (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Leaflet and menu (March 16), internal publications (1997), postcard, March 16, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- How to be a good waitress at the Moosewood Restaurant (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Brunch posters, instructions, cartoon, correspondence, information sheets, photographs, time line (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Clippings, posters, 1990-2008 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Borders/old art/flyers/parties, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Clipping, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Art work (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Misc. musicians’ agreements (Box 2, Folder 5)
- New signs (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 30th anniversary posters, misc., 2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Misc. moose art and other images (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Misc. ads, clippings, contest forms, 35 years posters, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Items for Web site (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Catering suggestions, employee handbooks, renovation proposal, misc., menus (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Press kit, bios of members (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 25 and still growing (clipping), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Misc. clippings, vendor list, time line, post card, Moosewood Restaurant News, letter, magnet, 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Operations and statistics notebook, 1998-2004 (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
- Magazine articles: Why, American Way, Bon Appétit, Vegetarian Times, Food and Wine, People, Better Homes and Gardens, 1991-2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Newspaper articles, 1985-1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Cooking for Health: reviews, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Clippings and articles, 1983-2008 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Articles 2001 and later (copies), 2001- (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Articles with brief mention of Moosewood, 2000-2004 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Fan letters and clippings, 1987-1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Articles, reviews, publicity, 1988-2005 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Self’s favorite restaurants, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Dishing up a delectable reputation, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Bon Appetit article+, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- 25th anniversary article, Asbury Park Press, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Developed recipes for Bon Appetit magazine, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Copies of best articles and magazine articles clipped, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Articles, mentions, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 32-37)
- Food products, 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
- Moosewood salad dressings (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Thanks you letters, acknowledgements for cooking classes (photos included) (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Wegman’s demo, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Special events, 2001-2009 (Box 2, Folder 43-46)
- Newspaper clippings (oversize) (Box 3)
- 2 sets of 50 recipe cards: "Soups and Stews" and "Farm Fresh Meals" (Box 3)
- Masters for product labels (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Publicity posters (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Calendar masters (Box 4, Folder 2)